SARA MORAKABIAN

188 Buckskin Drive ~ Van Alstyne, TX, 75495

(903)-744-5067

saramorakabian@gmail.com

RESUME PROFILE

Sara Morakabian is a twenty-one-year-old, high achieving student and employee, who is at the University of Texas. Sara is pursuing a Bachelor of Science and Arts in Biology with a Pre-Health Professions Certificate. Throughout High School and University, Sara has participated in a variety of memberships and organizations, in addition to holding employment. From numerous children to a variety of adults and elderly, Sara can successfully interact with and service anyone thanks to her history as a food service, camp counselor, office worker, classroom aide, university employee, club officer and so forth. She has talents across a wide range, in computer technology, musicianship, healthcare, and science, and a lot of independent and leadership experience.

EDUCATION & ACADEMIC ACCOMPLISHMENTS

The University of Texas at Austin (Spring 2019-

Current) GPA: 3.8

Major: Bachelor of Science and Arts in Biology, Pre-Health Professions Certificate (Expected May 2021)

Honors/Memberships

- Member of the UT Austin's Sanger Learning Center Student Advisory Board
- Member of the University of Texas Longhorn Band
- Member of the Sanger Learning Center Music Ensemble
- Biostatistics PLUS Facilitator
- Member of Future Doctors of America
- Researcher in Peptide Synthesis & Molecular Recognition in the Accelerated Research Initiative
- Outreach STEM UTeach (1 semester)
- Anime Club
- Healthcare & Business Inventors Program
 Practicum Inventor

<u>Grayson County Community College</u> (Summer 2015 –

Summer 2017 Credits earned: 28

Collin County Community College (Fall 2017-Fall 2018)

GPA: 3.5

Credits earned: 31

Degree: Associates of Science (AS)

Dean's List

Other Experience

- Proficient in Microsoft Office
- Proficient in R. ChemDraw
- Completed Introductory Python Training
- OSHA Safety and Health Training Course Completion
- Member of the Texas Association of Healthcare
 Volunteers at Wilson N. Jones Regional Medical Center
- American Red Cross Volunteer
- Sunrise Community Homeless Shelter Volunteer
- Assisted in production of education videos for wilderness medicine courses through the University of Colorado School of Medicine, Section of Wilderness & Emergency Medicine
- Musical Proficiency (Clarinet, Auxiliary Percussion, Accordion, Saxophone, Ukulele)

Research & Lab Experience

The University of Texas Accelerated Research Initiative Student Under Dr. Pedro Metola & PI Dr. Eric Anslyn Spring 2019

Solid Phase Peptide Synthesis

- Successfully created a GGGWC peptide used in bacterial research & learned peptide making process
 - Understand how to submit to LCMS and use a peptide synthesizer as well as various lab equipment
 - Washing, drying, shaking, creating solutions efficiently
 - o LCMS analysis

Fall 2020

UV-vis Chiral Analysis of a Boronic Acid Based Sensor

- Completed UV-vis spectra of different molecular based sensors that could be applied to pharmaceuticals
 - Spectroscopic Analysis and Use
 - Creating solutions & understanding buffers

SARA MORAKABIAN

188 Buckskin Drive ~ Van Alstyne, TX, 75495

(903)-744-5067

saramorakabian@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE

Braums Ice Cream and Dairy Stores – Van Alstyne, TX 7/2015- 02/2017

EMPLOYEE TRAINING OFFICER

Experience taking customer orders, preparing menu items, and interacting with customers. Maintaining restaurant front counters and drive-thru windows in addition to replacing inventories and food supplies when necessary, sanitizing dining rooms, work stations, and restrooms as needed.

- Cashier/Clerk
- Stocker
- Customer Service
- Sanitation/Cleaning
- Drive-Thru Operator

YMCA Collin County Adventure Camp - Anna, TX 05/2017 – 08/2017

CAMP COUNSELOR

Leadership position, camp counselor of groups of campers ranging in age from five to seventeen. Assist in all functions related to running of the camp, responsible for the well-being of a variety of campers including those afflicted with cancer, epilepsy, and a variety of other disabilities in various retreat groups. Motivated to positively interact with campers, parents, and other staff and inspire strong character values in youth.

- Resident & Overnight Camp
 Counselor
- Camp Equipment OperatorMaintain Discipline/Safety
- Childcare Experience
- Camp Activity Instructor/Overseer
- Group Leader/Camper Supervisor
- Outdoor/Nature Experience
- Camp Sanitation/Cleaning

McDonalds - Van Alstyne, TX 06/2014 – SEASONAL

CREW MEMBER

Furthering experience in customer service. Worked with largest and most diverse staff of employees to date. Located in a travel center, interacted with a plethora of different customers, shared space with other business. Assisted in areas where needed such as kitchen, stocking, and lobby assistant.

- Front end/cash handling
- Assisted with Cleanliness Maintenance
- Customer Greeter; Helped Introduce New Self-Serve System
- Delivered Prompt, Friendly Customer Service

UT Austin- Sanger Learning Center - Austin, TX 9/2019 - 12/2019

CHEMISTRY SUPPLEMENTAL INSTRUCTOR

Held biweekly sessions of practice information for Principles of General Chemistry I for STEM majors. Created worksheets and practiced to relay and practice information to sessions of students from 2-60. Facilitated interaction between students. Worked within chemistry department and attended weekly meetings in order to improve facilitation techniques.

- Created a Heterogenous Environment for Students at All Levels
- Developed Relevant Worksheets, Attended Students' Lectures
- Attended Workshops & Teaching Training

Texakona Coffee Lodge - Van Alstyne, Texas 02/2018 – SEASONAL

BARISTA & BAKER

Promotes coffee consumption in small town by educating customers; selling coffee and retail. Works to refer customers to main roastery for tours and increased retail purchases. Trains new members in preparing and serving a variety of coffee drinks along with pastries, snacks, and sandwiches

- Upselling/Knowledge of Coffee Industry and History
- Cash Drawer Audits
- Safe Drops/Opening
- Temperature Management
- Inventory Invoice Management
- Strong Customer Service & Education Skills

Subway - Van Alstyne, TX 06/2020 – SEASONAL

SANDWICH ARTISAN

Worked in travel center between Subway and Coffee Lodge. Assisted customers during explosive lunch rushes, ensured prep was made for each shift, increased dexterity.

- Diverse abilities between prep, making bread, dishes
- Successfully promoted seasonal and promotional items
- Assisted with app orders

Professional references and recommendations available upon request.